nbcbirdandpest.co.uk 2013-04-20

# Privacy Policy - for your safety - Bird & Pest Control Experts

NBC BIRD AND PEST SOLUTIONS LTD WEBSITE PRIVACY POLICY

### 1\. General

This website is owned and operated by NBC Bird and Pest Solutions Limited ("NBC" /"us"/ "our"/ "we") and accessible at URLs www.nbcbirdandpest.co.uk the controller of all personal data and/or sensitive personal data ("personal information") collected on this website ("Site").

We believe strongly in protecting the privacy of all Site users ("you"/ "your") and this privacy policy sets out how we use your personal information.

We are committed to protecting your privacy. We will only use the personal information that we collect about you in full compliance with the EU Data Protection Directive (95/46/EC) and subsidiary directives ("Directives"), as implemented in English law by the Data Protection Act 1998 and will continue to ensure that its policies and practices comply in all respects with any future laws and regulations in relation to your privacy.

### 2\. Your consent and acknowledgement

  1. Unless you have expressly indicated otherwise your use of the Site constitutes your consent to our collection use sharing and transfer of your personal information under the terms of this privacy policy; and
  2. You acknowledge and agree that our [Website Terms of Use](http://www.nbcbirdandpest.co.uk/terms-of-use/) apply to this privacy policy as if reproduced here in full;
  3. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THE TERMS OF OUR PRIVACY POLICY OR OUR [Website Terms of Use](http://www.nbcbirdandpest.co.uk/terms-of-use/) YOU MAY NOT USE OUR SITE.

### 3\. What personal information do we gather from you?

We gather personal information necessary to fulfil your order such as your name telephone number email address and postal address and any enquiries that you provide voluntarily when you contact us by e-mail or complete any on-line forms

The web server also collects data pertaining to every visitor including the IP address the length of time spent on the Site and the pages accessed when visiting the Site.

In order to provide you and other Site users with a personalised and valuable service we operate a voluntary personal information submission process. During submission a user is required to give contact information such as that described above.

We may ask you to provide us with information regarding your contact preferences in order to provide you with further correspondence about our products and services. You are not obliged to provide this information and you can opt out of this correspondence during registration or otherwise prior to submission of your details to us.

We use Google Analytics to measure site usage and understand how our visitors engage with our website. Google Analytics collects information anonymously and it reports website trends without identifying individual visitors. Analytics uses its own set of cookies to track visitor interactions. These cookies are used to store information, such as what time the current visit occurred, whether the visitor has been to the site before, and what site referred the visitor to the web page. For more information about Google's Privacy Policy and how Google uses cookies for Google Analytics please go to <http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/ads/#toc-analytics>

## 4\. How do we use the personal information that we gather from you?

Our main aim in gathering your personal information is to understand your needs and provide you with a better and customised service.

We will process all the personal information we collect and hold on you fairly and in accordance with applicable law. As further explained in this privacy policy we will ensure the quality and security of your personal information; and we will fully respect your rights interests and fundamental freedoms with regard to your personal information.

We will only collect record process and/or store on our databases personal information which is needed:

  1. To improve our products and services or otherwise fulfil our contractual obligations towards you our customers, our prospective franchisees and our business partners within the NBC Network (as defined below in clause 5) as may exist from time to time; and/or
  2. to serve our legitimate business interests such as administration including internal record keeping, credit assessment marketing, prospective franchisee vetting or to comply with legal requirements; and/or
  3. in order that our representatives may by telephone or ordinary mail proactively follow up your enquires submitted to our Site about our products and services as part of our customer care procedures and/or reply to your e-mailed or otherwise voluntarily submitted questions enquiries and requirements that you may have; and/or
  4. in order that we may periodically send you promotional information about our products and/or services marketing information and news that we consider may be of interest to you (for example relating to our new product or service offerings or improvements or special offers or other promotions and offers): 
    1. 1\. by e-mail or other electronic communication with your prior consent (eg, by 'opting in' via tick or otherwise); or
    2. 2\. by ordinary post or other non-electronic communication unless you (on registration/submission of details or subsequently) 'opt out' via e-mail or by unticking an on-line tick box or by registering with the appropriate Preference Service

We may also use aggregate personal information and statistics for the purposes of monitoring Site usage in order to help us develop the Site and our service and may provide such aggregate and anonymised personal information to third parties.

If you inform us that you no longer wish us to contact you for any one or all of the reasons stated above in this clause 4(a) to (d) inclusive then we will cease contacting you although you acknowledge that this may prevent us from providing information about our products and/or services to you or inhibit the quality of service provided to you.

If we record or monitor telephone calls to and from any customers for staff training and quality control purposes we will first inform you that such recording and monitoring is taking place.

If at some time in the future we wish to use your personal information in ways other than those set out in this privacy policy and requiring your prior consent then we will notify you about this and seek your permission to do so.

### 5\. Sharing of personal information

We may share personal information within the NBC network; by this expression, we mean NBC including together with its/their officers, employees, agents, distributors, consultants contractors (including data processing agencies ("processors")), suppliers and certain selected third party organisations and NBC Bird and Pest Solutions (Franchising) Limited licensees (" **NBC Network** "). The NBC Network will process your personal information in accordance with this privacy policy and all privacy and communications legislation.

We will not share with or sell lease or otherwise distribute your personal information to any third party organisations outside of the NBC Network without first obtaining your permission to do so. In particular, we will not release your personal information to our authorised direct marketing agents without first obtaining your prior consent.

We currently do not envisage transferring your personal information outside of the EEA. However, providing that we do so lawfully and for the sole purpose of fulfilling our contractual obligations to you you agree to our transferring personal information about you to any member or members of the NBC Network outside of the European Economic Area ("EEA"). You acknowledge that some countries where other facilities or companies or third party organisations are situated may have no data protection legislation or laws which are less rigorous than the legislation introduced by the member states of the European Union and the EEA. Accordingly, in the event that we need to transfer your personal information to any member or members of the NBC Network outside of the EEA for the sole purpose of fulfilling our contractual obligations with you you acknowledge and agree that we will use reasonable efforts to procure (but cannot guarantee) that such facilities companies or third party organisations give binding contractual undertakings in order to ensure the same level of protection for the processing carried out in these countries as within the European Economic Area.

Of course if we need your further specific and express consent to do this, we will obtain it before transferring any personal information.

In all cases, any use of your personal information by the NBC Network which has been instigated by us will comply with this privacy policy.

You acknowledge that we reserve the right to use or disclose any personal information as needed to satisfy any law regulation or otherwise or legal request to protect and defend the integrity of the Site (including to enforce our [Website Terms of Use](http://www.nbcbirdandpest.co.uk/terms-of-use/) or this privacy policy) and you agree to fulfil our requests and/or to cooperate in any law enforcement or regulatory investigation.

Save for that stated above we do not transfer share or disclose personal information we have collected from you in connection with our on or off-line activities to third parties outside the NBC Network.

If in the future a third party organisation acquires us or substantially all of our assets including without limitation our database(s) (whether by merger, acquisition, reorganisation or otherwise) you acknowledge and agree that your information including personal information may well be one of the transferred assets.

### 6\. Cookies

A cookie is an alphanumeric identifier which asks permission to be placed on your hard drive through your web browser when you visit our Site. Once you agree (or your browser agrees automatically if you have set it up in that way) it enables our own system to recognise you when you visit our Site to track the pages you looked at while visiting our Site and therefore to improve our Site and tailor the service to you. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences. For example, when you visit an electronic store such as ours a cookie makes it easier to shop by allowing you to place things into a shopping basket; the basket itself is not a cookie; the cookie is placed on your hard drive and keeps track of your basket versus others in use at the same time. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system. Denial of a traffic log cookie may prevent you from using the Site. Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better Site by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you other than the data you choose to share with us. This practice is strictly enforced. We know that people have concerns about cookies but we believe that the benefit that you and we gain from their proper use is worthwhile.

You may set up your web browser (Microsoft Internet Explorer or Netscape Navigator) to notify you of cookie placement requests or decline cookies completely (although you acknowledge that declining them may prevent you from being able to use the Site properly or at all). You can delete the files that contain cookies - those files are stored as part of your Internet browser. To remove cookies from your web browser or to obtain further details on cookies including information on persistent and session cookies please go to [www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies).

### 7\. Protection of your personal information

The internet is not a secure medium and we cannot absolutely guarantee the security of your personal information as set out below. We will however use all reasonable efforts to protect the information you provide to us.

We will only provide access to personal information on you to those members of the NBC Network who we consider need such access in order to carry out our contractual obligations to you. We have taken appropriate steps to ensure the security of personal information whether it is stored in computer systems paper files or other storage media. Access to your information is restricted in our offices. Only members of the NBC Network who need the information to perform a specific job are granted access to personally identifiable information.

Further our Site and associated databases are protected by certified firewalls in order to protect your personal information from access by unauthorised persons and against unlawful processing. The servers that we store personally identifiable information on are kept in a secure environment. The Site uses the latest technology with full backups. Password protection is provided for all registered users of this Site. All outgoing and incoming email is scanned for viruses.

The NBC Network expects the same high standards of security and confidentiality of any processors agents or sub-contractors we use to process data for us. To help us keep your information confidential you are recommended to keep your password secret; change your password on a regular basis; and never distribute the URL's for pages that you have looked at while logged in as a registered customer.

### 8\. Your rights: Accessing, updating and retention of personal information

We will employ effective procedures and safeguards to ensure that the personal information we hold on you are adequate relevant and not excessive in relation to the purposes for which they were obtained as well as accurate and up-to-date. Where you inform us of any inaccuracies in the personal information we hold we will correct and where appropriate delete incorrect personal information. Retention periods are in place to ensure that personal information are only stored whilst they are required for the purposes in question or to meet administrative legal and regulatory requirements. Where personal information are no longer required by us we will ensure that they are disposed of in a secure manner.

You have the qualified right to request sight of all the personal information we hold on you. Should you wish to have access to all or a particular part of your personal information please contact our Data Compliance Officer by [enquiries@nbcbirdandpest.co.uk](mailto:enquiries@nbcbirdandpest.co.uk). Such access will be granted in accordance with the requirements of national legislation and subject to any discretionary allowance for us to make a charge payable by you to cover our administration costs incurred in providing you with such personal information. Such payment is to be made on application for access to your personal information and is to be no more than the maximum stipulated by national legislation (if applicable). The information will be forwarded to you within an appropriate period of time in accordance with national legislation, but in any event no more than forty (40) days from the date of such request for access.

Where any discrepancies are discovered following your enquiry we will take immediate steps to validate and where appropriate correct our records to ensure that your personal information are accurate and kept up-to-date. We will confirm the actions taken in writing to you within an appropriate period of time in accordance with national legislation but in any event no more than forty (40) days after receiving your request to amend our records.

### 9\. Links to third party websites

The Site may from time to time include links to third party internet websites which are controlled and maintained by others. These links are included solely for your convenience and do not constitute any endorsement by us of the websites linked or referred to including the products and/or services featured on those websites, nor do we have any control over or knowledge of any privacy practices or content of any such websites. Further, we have not reviewed these third party websites and do not make any representations regarding the availability or content or accuracy of materials on such websites. If you decide to access third party websites through links on the Site, you do so at your own risk. Your use of third party websites is subject to any privacy policies of those websites which you should read immediately prior to submitting personal information to those websites

### 10\. Changes to our privacy policy

We reserve the right at our sole discretion to add to or change the terms of this privacy policy. If we publish any changes we will let you know by posting such changes to this page and/or by posting notification of change to our Site homepage. Once we have posted any such changes it is then your responsibility as a user to ensure that you are aware of such changes from time to time. Changes will become effective 24 hours after first posting and you will be deemed to have accepted any change if you continue to access the Site after that time.

### 11\. Email Newsletters Opt Ins and Opt Outs

Where you have the option to subscribe to various email services or unsubscribe from receiving ordinary mail or telephone or other contact services which we offer relating to promotional information about our products and/or services marketing information and news that we consider may be of interest to you (for example relating to our new product or service offerings or improvements or special offers or other promotions and offers). If you initially tick the box or otherwise opt in but subsequently no longer wish to receive such communication from us, please send an appropriate [enquiries@nbcbirdandpest.co.uk](mailto:enquiries@nbcbirdandpest.co.uk) and your details will be removed from our electronic mailing lists. If you initially do not opt out of receiving non-electronic promotional information, but subsequently wish to do so, please contact us and your details will be removed from our non-electronic contact lists

If you inform us that you no longer wish us to contact you for any one or all of the reasons stated above in this clause 4(a) to (d) inclusive then we will cease contacting you although you acknowledge that this may prevent us from providing the products and/or services to you or inhibit the quality of service provided to you.

### 12\. Questions or complaints: [contact us](http://www.nbcbirdandpest.co.uk/contact/)

We reiterate that by submitting your personal information to us you consent to our (including our business partners' within the NBC Network) use of that personal information as set out in this privacy policy. If you have any questions concerns or comments about this privacy policy and/or our collection use or the accuracy of your personal information or if you wish to see any of the personal information we hold on you or if you wish us to stop processing your personal information for any particular purpose or purposes then please contact us by [enquiries@nbcbirdandpest.co.uk](mailto:enquiries@nbcbirdandpest.co.uk) or by writing to The Data Compliance Officer NBC Bird and Pest Solutions Limited (Registered Company No. 3475126) of Abbotsgate House, Hollow Road, Bury St Edmunds, Suffolk, IP32 7FA (Registered Office Address)

© 2007 2010 Limited. NBC Bird and Pest Solutions Limited. All rights reserved.

Go back to top of Page
